<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xml:id="chaining_rules.xml"
         version="5.0"
         xml:lang="en"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd
           http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/xlink.xsd">

    <para>The chaining rules define the behaviour of the broker when forwarding SIP requests or responses as well
    as handling particular error responses.
    </para>

    <para>The chain of services is determined by the <emphasis>servicekey</emphasis> parameter present in the
        Route header of the initial INVITE. The services are called with separate dialogs where INVITE sent towards
        next service in the chain contains the headers and the body present in the incoming INVITE from the previous service.
        The broker only modifies the headers responsible for proper message routing.
        The different incoming dialogs within a single orchestration session are correlated by means of additional
        header <emphasis>P-Original-Dialog-ID</emphasis> set by the broker in the outgoing INVITEs.
    </para>

    <para>All the SIP responses and requests other than INVITE are chained on the dialogs established by INVITE.
        The requests are forwarded in either direction with respect to SIP forwarding rules.
    </para>

    <para>The orchestration chain may define two ways to deal with error response to INVITEs: <emphasis>ERROR</emphasis> logic
        and <emphasis>SKIP</emphasis> logic. When certain error response indicates SKIP logic, the broker excludes
        responding service from the chain and sends INVITE to the next service
        (or IM-SCF B leg if response received from last chained service).
        An error response indicating STOP logic is forwarded back to the previous service. Additionally,
        the chaining state of the responding service is rolled back as it was never executed within current session.
        The service that receives the error response has the control on the chaining session.
        It therefore might decide forward response back (on its A leg), send another INVITE requests towards the broker
        or initiate out-of-orchestration session (see <xref linkend="auxiliary_session.xml"/>).
    </para>

    <para>INVITE sending errors are considered as other error responses and checked against the error logic rules.
        <emphasis>Client Transaction timeout</emphasis> for INVITE is mapped to <emphasis>REQUEST_TIMEOUT (408)</emphasis>.
        <emphasis>Transaction layer error</emphasis> for INVITE is mapped to <emphasis>SERVICE_UNAVAILABLE (503)</emphasis>.
    </para>

    <para>The session is kept alive by the broker until all involved dialogs are terminated.
    </para>

    <para>The orchestration configuration is described in <xref linkend="orchestration_configuration.xml"/>
    </para>

</section>